<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Recent Content on Curiosity &amp; the Geek Blog </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 13:27:02 IST</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>A color theme based on the Nile</title>
      <link>/blog/nile-color-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 13:27:02 IST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/nile-color-theme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://adobe.ly/1xRo7U6&#34; alt=&#34;Click to open in Adobe Kuler&#34;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&#34;Nile color theme&#34; class=&#34;pure-img-responsive&#34; src=&#34;/img/nile.svg&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lazy cruise down the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nile&#34;&gt;Nile river&lt;/a&gt; from Aswan to Luxor with
stops at archeological sites was of the more memorable experiences my wife and I enjoyed in Egypt.
What struck us most was the unique blend of colors on the Nile riverbank that arises due to the fact
that in much of Egypt, the civilization is but a thin cultivated strip of green on either side of
the river in the middle of the desert under the largely cloudless blue sky.  After my wife &amp;amp; I
recently reminiscenced about our trip, I tried to convert our memories of colors into the color
theme above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Nile riverbank&#34; class=&#34;pure-img-responsive&#34; src=&#34;/img/Nile.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Android Studio (or Eclipse ADT) work on 64-bit Ubuntu Saucy 13.10 or Trusty 14.04</title>
      <link>/blog/android-studio-on-trusty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 06:10:34 IST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/android-studio-on-trusty/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;The Issue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting Android Studio (or Eclipse Android Development Tools) to run successfully on 64-bit (ie. amd64)
installations of the newer Ubuntu (or underlying Debian) distributions like Trusty Thar (14.04)
is not a very straightforward process. While the IDE you download itself will work assuming you have JDK
installed, it will throw a bunch of build errors when you try to build any app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Why does this happen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The build errors happen because the Android &lt;code&gt;build-tools&lt;/code&gt; are actually 32-bit (ie. i386) binaries dynamically linked
to several 32-bit libraries. For instance, this is what the the &lt;code&gt;file&lt;/code&gt; outputs on my installation
of the &lt;code&gt;aapt&lt;/code&gt; tool in the &lt;code&gt;build-tools&lt;/code&gt; folder within the sdk
    file aapt
    aapt: ELF 32-bit LSB  shared object, Intel 80386, version 1 (SYSV), dynamically linked
    (uses shared libs), for GNU/Linux 2.6.8, not stripped&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the 64-bit installations of Linux can run 32-bit binaries, they do not come pre-installed with
the necessary 32-bit libraries pre-installed. Googling throws up dozens of posts advising installation
of the &lt;code&gt;ia32-libs&lt;/code&gt; but this advise is unfortunately outdated. Newer versions of Ubuntu from 13.10 Saucy
onwards have &lt;a href=&#34;http://askubuntu.com/questions/359156/how-do-you-run-a-32-bit-program-on-a-64-bit-version-of-ubuntu/359184#359184&#34;&gt;removed&lt;/a&gt;
the &lt;code&gt;ia32-libs&lt;/code&gt; package and rely fully on &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.debian.org/Multiarch&#34;&gt;Multiarch&lt;/a&gt; which is a
much more comprehensive solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;The Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get Android Studio (or Eclipse ADT) build properly on the newer 64 bit Ubuntu releases like 13.10
Saucy or 14.04 Trusty you need to add the 32-bit i386 library dependencies as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo dpkg --add-architecture i386
sudo apt-get install libc6:i386 libncurses5:i386 libstdc++6:i386 zlib1g:i386
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it! You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t get the build errors any more! Happy app development!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoAniGiffy: A versatile animated GIF creator</title>
      <link>/opensource/goanigiffy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 05:31:44 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/opensource/goanigiffy/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Animated GIFs have made a comeback as very convenient ways to post short video clips or slideshows on the web
without needing Flash, YouTube or Flickr embedding. Their convenience often outweights image quality limitations
(only 256 colors palette) and poor compression for basic uses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While a number of free web services have sprung up to convert videos to animated GIFs, they do not typically
allow editing beyond basic trimming. You &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; use a traditional video editor of course but the free ones
are not exactly intuitive and have limited utility in creating slideshows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;GoAniGiffy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GoAniGiffy is a small utility written in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.golang.org&#34;&gt;Go Programming language&lt;/a&gt; that was born out
of the need to convert my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=esBDMSmbg3E&#34;&gt;demo video&lt;/a&gt; of
&lt;a href=&#34;/opensource/ardgrafix6100/&#34;&gt;ArdGrafix6100&lt;/a&gt; into an &lt;a href=&#34;/img/ardgrafix6100demo.gif&#34;&gt;animated GIF&lt;/a&gt; for
hosting on GitHub Pages. This video was originally shot on a phone camera and I wanted to crop it
to show only the LCD Display with some scaling and rotation. I tried MPlayer first but found it does
not use good dithering in downsampling the video to 256 colors for GIFs resulting in poor splotchy images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GoAniGiffy converts a set of alphabetically sorted image files (eg. video frames extracted as JPEGs)
into an animated GIF with the options to crop, scale, rotate &amp;amp; flip source images. Downsampling
and Scaling are done with high quality algorithms from the &lt;code&gt;github.com/disintegration/imaging&lt;/code&gt; library by
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.github.com/disintegration/imaging&#34;&gt;Grigory Dryapak&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.org/pkg/image/draw/#Drawer&#34;&gt;Go Standard Library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/srinathh/goanigiffy/tree/master/binaries&#34;&gt;Zipped executable binaries&lt;/a&gt; are available for Linux
&amp;amp; Windows in both 32 bit &amp;amp; 64 bit flavors. Download the zip appropriate to your OS and extract somewhere in your
system PATH.  If you want to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/srinathh/goanigiffy&#34;&gt;build from source&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;go get&lt;/code&gt; should fetch the imported libraries &amp;amp; build the utility
in your $GOPATH/bin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;go get github.com/srinathh/goanigiffy
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GoAniGiffy is a command line utility to be used from the terminal - no GUIs for the present. Use GoAniGiffy with
a command line of the form below. All parameters are optional and have sane default values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;goanigiffy -src=&amp;quot;&amp;lt;file name pattern&amp;gt;&amp;quot; -&amp;lt;option&amp;gt;=&amp;lt;value&amp;gt; -&amp;lt;option&amp;gt;=&amp;lt;value&amp;gt;... -dest=&amp;quot;&amp;lt;gif file name&amp;gt;&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Image Options&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-src = &amp;quot;&amp;lt;file name pattern&amp;gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This specifies the input images using a file name pattern. You can use
standard wildcards or a &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.org/pkg/path/filepath/#Match&#34;&gt;more complex pattern&lt;/a&gt; supported by
the &lt;code&gt;path/filepath&lt;/code&gt; package in Go Language. GoAniGiffy will find matching files and sort them
alphabetically before processing which makes it easy to use GoAniGiffy with numbered image frames extracted
from videos.  If you do not specfiy &lt;code&gt;-src&lt;/code&gt;, GoAniGiffy will use &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;*.jpg&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; as the file pattern.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-dest=&amp;quot;&amp;lt;gif file name&amp;gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This specifies the file name and path for the output gif file. If you do not specifiy an
output file, GoAniGiffy will by default create &amp;ldquo;movie.gif&amp;rdquo; in the current folder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-delay=&amp;lt;integer value&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This specifies the delay between frames of the image in multiples of hundredths of a second.
A value of 3 which is the default should theoritically give you 33 frames per second close to the default video speed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Cropping Options&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-cropleft=&amp;lt;integer value&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you want to crop the images, specify the left co-ordinate of the top-left corner of the
rectangle you would like to crop here. The default value is 0&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-croptop=&amp;lt;integer value&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you want to crop the images, specify the top co-ordinate of the top-left corner of the
rectangle you would like to crop here. The default value is 0&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-cropwidth=&amp;lt;integer value&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you want to crop the images, specify the width of the rectangle you would like to crop
here. The default value is -1 which specifies the full image width.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-cropheigh=&amp;lt;integer value&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you want to crop the images, specify the height of the rectangle you would like to crop
here. The default value is -1 which specifies the full image height.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;Other Image Editing Options&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-scale=&amp;lt;decimal value&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you want to scale the images, specify a scaling factor here in terms of decimals. For instance
to make the animated GIF half the size as source images use -scale=0.5. The default value is 1.0
which specifies no scaling&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-rotate=&amp;lt;0 or 90 or 180 or 270&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you want the images to be rotated, specify the rotation angle in degrees here. Arbitrary
rotations are not supported and you can only use 90, 180 or 270. The default value is 0 which specifies no rotation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-flip=&amp;lt;&amp;quot;none&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;horizontal&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;vertical&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you want the images to be flipped, specify &amp;ldquo;horizontal&amp;rdquo; or
&amp;ldquo;vertical&amp;rdquo; here. The default value is &amp;ldquo;none&amp;rdquo; which specifies no flipping&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_6&#34;&gt;Other Options&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-verbose&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
By default GoAniGiffy will process the files and exit without any messages unless there is an error.
Specifying -verbose will show in-process messages as the individual frames get processed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_7&#34;&gt;Extracting Frames from Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to convert a video to an animated GIF, you first need to extract frames. I use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mplayerhq.hu/&#34;&gt;MPlayer&lt;/a&gt;
with a command line like below to extract JPEG frames. The &lt;code&gt;-ss 6 -endpos 8&lt;/code&gt; options specify extraction between the 6th and 8th seconds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mplayer -vo jpeg:quality=80 -nosound -ss 6 -endpos 8 vid.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_8&#34;&gt;Example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This command line creates a movie.gif from the images in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/srinathh/goanigiffy/tree/master/sample&#34;&gt;sample folder&lt;/a&gt;
of the source repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;goanigiffy -src=&amp;quot;sample/*.jpg&amp;quot; -dest=&amp;quot;sample/movie.gif&amp;quot; -cropleft=100 -croptop=280 -cropwidth=550 -cropheight=351 -scale=0.5 -rotate=270 -verbose
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original frames are processed into an animated GIF below showing  only the LCD Panel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;ArdGrafix6100 Screenshot&#34; class=&#34;pure-img-responsive&#34; src=&#34;/img/00000002.jpg&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&#34;ArdGrafix6100 Screenshot&#34; class=&#34;pure-img-responsive&#34; src=&#34;/img/ardgrafix6100demo.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_9&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GoAniGiffy code is licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/srinathh/goanigiffy/blob/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;Apache v2.0&lt;/a&gt; license.
All other media files &amp;amp; documentation in the repository is licened under &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using FuseCompress to compress folders in Ubuntu</title>
      <link>/blog/fusecompress-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 09:06:32 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/fusecompress-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Why consider using Fusecompress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many light-weight Notebooks and all Chromebooks today come with balzingly fast but
limited capacity Solid State Drives (SSDs) on the theory that people store much of
their data in the cloud. However, to use these as Android development machines,
you typically do need to store space hogs like sources and library documentation,
emulator images etc locally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fusecompress is a great little legacy utility that uses the FUSE (File System
in User Space) library to provide an on the fly compressed mountable filesystem
that in effect lets you compress specific directories in manner completely
transparent to all other programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use my HP Chromebook 14 loaded with Ubuntu 14.04 via the ChrUbuntu on a lean
9GB partition as my primary development machine. I use fusecompress to compress
offline documentation for Android and Python and the huge Android Emulator
system images. This reduces the SSD footprint considerably with barely any impact
on load times. The Emulator startup does become significantly slower but I need to
to do this only once each session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Installing fusecompress on Ubuntu 14.04&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fusecompress however is not available in the standard Ubuntu repositories and
must be compiled from source. Given the legacy nature of the codebase, it&amp;rsquo;s
a bit tricky to compile for novices. This blog post outlines the process step-by-step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Install Aptitude&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When I was using apt-get to install the dependency library sources, I found in
a couple of cases the latest development releases of the libraries had
conflicts and I had to regress to the previous version to install them.
Aptitude does a much better job of solving for conflicts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install aptitude
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Install the auto build tools&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If they&amp;rsquo;re not installed on your system already, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to install
autoconf and automake to be able to build from source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo aptitude install autoconf automake libtool
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Install compression algorithms development packages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Next install the development packages for compression algorithms supported
by fusecompress - LZO, LZMA, ZLib &amp;amp; BZ2. I ran into trouble in the LZO package
where I had to revert from the 2.06-1.2ubuntu1.1 version to 2.06-1.2ubuntu1
version. Aptitude gives you a series of menu choices to handle this smoothly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo aptitude install zlib1g-dev libbz2-dev liblzma-dev liblzo2-dev
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Install the FUSE development package&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo aptitude install libfuse-dev
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download the fusecompress sources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You can checkout the fusecompress source from Google Code with SubVersion.
In today&amp;rsquo;s world of distributed version control systems like Git &amp;amp; Mercurial,
using SubVersion may seem quaint but that&amp;rsquo;s the cost of using a stable legacy
package like FuseCompress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo aptitude install subversion
svn checkout http://fusecompress.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/ fusecompress-read-only
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Run the fusecompress build process
Change to the folder where you&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded the fusecompress sources and
run the following commands. Put the generated fusecompress binary somewhere
in your system path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./autogen.sh
./configure
make
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Using fusecompress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The least disruptive way I found to use fusecompress is to simply mount the compressed
folders exactly where they currently are. The key thing to remember while using
fusecompress is that it compress files when they get written to disk. So files that
are already in the folder won&amp;rsquo;t automatically get compressed. The way I typically
manage this is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rename the directory you want to compress&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mv directoryname temporaryname
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create an empty directory with the old name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir directoryname
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fusecompress the directory&lt;/strong&gt;
The default compression algorithm used is LZO which is very fast. You can also
use LZMA as indicated below to get a better compression ratio. You maw want to
add this line to your ~/.profile to automount on boot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;fusecompress directoryname
fusecompress -c lzma directoryname
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Move back all the contents&lt;/strong&gt;
Since Fusecompress will now compress each of the files as it is moved back, this
step will take quite a bit of time depending on the amount of data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd temporaryname
mv *.* ../directoryname
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArdGrafix6100: Fast Arduino driver for Nokia 6100 Color LCDs</title>
      <link>/opensource/ardgrafix6100/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 04:23:21 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/opensource/ardgrafix6100/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;ArdGrafix6100 is a fast and full-featured graphics library for interfacing the Nokia 6100 color
graphics LCD with Arduino. It uses hardware SPI &amp;amp; block write features of the graphics controller
on the LCD to boost graphics performance &amp;amp; supports advanced features like proportional fonts
in a tiny RAM footprint. The Philips PF8833 controller is currently supported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;ArdGrafix6100 Screenshot&#34; class=&#34;pure-img-responsive&#34; src=&#34;/img/ardgrafix6100.jpg&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&#34;ArdGrafix6100 Screenshot&#34; class=&#34;pure-img-responsive&#34; src=&#34;/img/ardgrafix6100demo.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/p/ardgrafix6100/&#34;&gt;Get the Library&lt;/a&gt; from Google Code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Fast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses ATmega SPI peripherals &amp;amp; ports for high - performance graphics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses block-write features of LCD controller to speed up writes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Full Featured&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports Proportional Fonts - a 14px height font is included by default!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implements all standard graphic primitives &amp;amp; utility classes like &amp;ldquo;xy&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;rectangle&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Practical&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fonts implemented programatically using OOP to conserve SRAM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses only AVR LIBC functions to ensure easy portability beyond Arduino&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&#34;&gt;Apache License, Version 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FullScreenWrapper2: Python GUI framework for Android</title>
      <link>/opensource/fullscreenwrapper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 04:24:12 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/opensource/fullscreenwrapper/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;FullScreenWapper2 is a GUI Framework for developing full screen apps using the FullScreenUI API functions provided by
&lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/p/android-scripting/&#34;&gt;Scripting Layer for Android (SL4A)&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href=&#34;Shttps://code.google.com/p/python-for-android/&#34;&gt;Python-for-Android&lt;/a&gt;
It enables Python SL4A scripts to get a look &amp;amp; feel similar to Android Java apps using the same Views used by native
Java apps XML Layouts and provides pythonic access to events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed eventloop &amp;amp; a layout stack enabling easy parent-&amp;gt;child-&amp;gt;parent transitions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EventHandler classes with event-matching functions pre-built for standard View events like click,itemclick(ListView) and key&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device Sensors &amp;amp; other similar SL4A/Custom events can also be caught &amp;amp; managed eventloop + EventHandler class&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pythonic access to the views and properties of the layout (ie. MainLayout.views.txt_label.background = &amp;ldquo;#FFAA00AA&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Get it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full documentation &amp;amp; library download is available at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/p/python-for-android/wiki/fullscreenwrapper2&#34;&gt;Python-for-Android Wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Framework Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;FullScreenWrapper2 framework design&#34; class=&#34;pure-img-responsive&#34; src=&#34;/img/fullscreenwrapper2.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;FullScreenWrapper2 framework design&#34; class=&#34;pure-img-responsive&#34; src=&#34;/img/fullscreenwrapper2_demo_screenshots.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World Web Servers in Python &amp; Go</title>
      <link>/blog/simplehttpservers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 05:59:29 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/simplehttpservers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: This is a simple post primarily written to learn markdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello World programs are the first programs typically introduced in any
programming language tutorial. However, in our modern era of web applications
they are not particularly insightful into the strenghts of a language to support
web development. In this article, we compare Hello World web servers written in
Python &amp;amp; Go languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Go Language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go Language&lt;/a&gt; released by Google is notable for its terse C Language inspired
syntax (indeed &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ken_Thompson is one of the inventors&#34;&gt;Ken Thompson&lt;/a&gt;
that nevertheless removes a lot of boilerplate. It has a unique approach to concurrency
and derives high performance from being a compiled language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go comes with extensive support for developing web applications within its
standard library including a robust templating solution. For serving simple static
or dynamic driven websites, onerarely need anything more than this.
For fancier applications, third party libraries provide more complex routers,
context packages etc. The &lt;a href=&#34;/code/helloworld.go&#34;&gt;Hello World&lt;/a&gt; web server is
effectively just 3 lines of code and can support many concurrent connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;package main

import (
    &amp;quot;fmt&amp;quot;
    &amp;quot;log&amp;quot;
    &amp;quot;net/http&amp;quot;
)

func main() {
    http.HandleFunc(&amp;quot;/&amp;quot;, func(w http.ResponseWriter, r *http.Request) {
        fmt.Fprintf(w, &amp;quot;Hello World&amp;quot;)
    })
    log.Fatal(http.ListenAndServe(&amp;quot;:8080&amp;quot;, nil))
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org/&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; is among the simplest of modern programming languages to learn due to its guiding
philosophy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://legacy.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0020/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;There should be one and preferably only one obvious way to do it&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
Python&amp;rsquo;s ease and a large base of mature third party libraries has made it a language
of choice among startups looking to iterate their minimum viable product quickly accepting
the performance penalty of an interpreted language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Python&amp;rsquo;s standard library has been designed for a prior era and it is definitely
not as simple to spin up a &lt;a href=&#34;/code/helloworld.py&#34;&gt;Hello World&lt;/a&gt; webserver as in Go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;import BaseHTTPServer

HOST_NAME = &#39;localhost&#39;
PORT_NUMBER = 8080

class MyHandler(BaseHTTPServer.BaseHTTPRequestHandler):
    def do_GET(s):
        s.send_response(200)
        s.send_header(&amp;quot;Content-type&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;text/text&amp;quot;)
        s.end_headers()
        s.wfile.write(&amp;quot;Hello World&amp;quot;)

if __name__ == &#39;__main__&#39;:
    server_class = BaseHTTPServer.HTTPServer
    httpd = server_class((HOST_NAME, PORT_NUMBER), MyHandler)
    try:
        httpd.serve_forever()
    except KeyboardInterrupt:
        pass
    httpd.server_close()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However modern web development with Python typically relies on one of the
many third party web frameworks, notably &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djangoproject.com/&#34;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;, to speed up web development.
As an example, look at the simplification coming from the popular &lt;a href=&#34;http://flask.pocoo.org/&#34;&gt;Flask&lt;/a&gt; micro-framework.
However, Python&amp;rsquo;s lack of in-built support for easy concurrency means that often,
jury-rigged solutions need to be employed in production to scale&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;from flask import Flask
app = Flask(__name__)

@app.route(&amp;quot;/&amp;quot;)
def hello():
    return &amp;quot;Hello World!&amp;quot;

if __name__ == &amp;quot;__main__&amp;quot;:
    app.run()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Hariharan Srinath</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 02:50:25 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been driven by curiosity since my childhood and my life took a decidedly geeky turn at the age of eleven
in early 90s when I taught myself computer programming in the BASIC Language from IBM Personal Computer manuals
in my father&amp;rsquo;s office. Though I have pursued other avenues in higher education and career, coding has been a
lifelong hobby to which I have recently added tinkering with hobby electronics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have degrees in Metallurgical Engineering (&lt;a href=&#34;http://iitbhu.ac.in/&#34;&gt;Indian Institute of Technology, Benaras
Hindu University, Varanasi&lt;/a&gt;) and Management (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iimahd.ernet.in/&#34;&gt;Indian Institute of Management, Ahmedabad&lt;/a&gt;).
I contributed to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.saimm.co.za/Conferences/MoltenSlags2004/077-Ekengard.pdf&#34;&gt;paper on steel-making&lt;/a&gt;
during my undergraduate internship in the Royal Institute of Technology, Stockholm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been working at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pg.com&#34;&gt;Procter &amp;amp; Gamble&lt;/a&gt; since 2006 in the field of &lt;a href=&#34;http://india.experiencepg.com/home/consumer_market_knowledge0.html&#34;&gt;consumer insights &amp;amp; analytics&lt;/a&gt;.
The major area of expertise I have developed over the years is in emerging market sales &amp;amp;
distribution recently leading analytic capabilities in this space globally. I also have significant experience in the
areas of traditional &amp;amp; digital media planning, modern retail, segmentation, trial/sampling programs and application
of behavioral science to consumer communications.  I currently work in a global innovation role focused on
developing new insights &amp;amp; analytics capabilities using emerging technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am based out of Mumbai, married to Deepa and we have a daughter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>