<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Fusecompress on Curiosity &amp; the Geek Blog </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>/tags/fusecompress/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 09:06:32 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using FuseCompress to compress folders in Ubuntu</title>
      <link>/blog/fusecompress-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 09:06:32 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/fusecompress-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Why consider using Fusecompress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many light-weight Notebooks and all Chromebooks today come with balzingly fast but
limited capacity Solid State Drives (SSDs) on the theory that people store much of
their data in the cloud. However, to use these as Android development machines,
you typically do need to store space hogs like sources and library documentation,
emulator images etc locally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fusecompress is a great little legacy utility that uses the FUSE (File System
in User Space) library to provide an on the fly compressed mountable filesystem
that in effect lets you compress specific directories in manner completely
transparent to all other programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use my HP Chromebook 14 loaded with Ubuntu 14.04 via the ChrUbuntu on a lean
9GB partition as my primary development machine. I use fusecompress to compress
offline documentation for Android and Python and the huge Android Emulator
system images. This reduces the SSD footprint considerably with barely any impact
on load times. The Emulator startup does become significantly slower but I need to
to do this only once each session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Installing fusecompress on Ubuntu 14.04&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fusecompress however is not available in the standard Ubuntu repositories and
must be compiled from source. Given the legacy nature of the codebase, it&amp;rsquo;s
a bit tricky to compile for novices. This blog post outlines the process step-by-step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Install Aptitude&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When I was using apt-get to install the dependency library sources, I found in
a couple of cases the latest development releases of the libraries had
conflicts and I had to regress to the previous version to install them.
Aptitude does a much better job of solving for conflicts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install aptitude
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Install the auto build tools&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If they&amp;rsquo;re not installed on your system already, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to install
autoconf and automake to be able to build from source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo aptitude install autoconf automake libtool
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Install compression algorithms development packages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Next install the development packages for compression algorithms supported
by fusecompress - LZO, LZMA, ZLib &amp;amp; BZ2. I ran into trouble in the LZO package
where I had to revert from the 2.06-1.2ubuntu1.1 version to 2.06-1.2ubuntu1
version. Aptitude gives you a series of menu choices to handle this smoothly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo aptitude install zlib1g-dev libbz2-dev liblzma-dev liblzo2-dev
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Install the FUSE development package&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo aptitude install libfuse-dev
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download the fusecompress sources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You can checkout the fusecompress source from Google Code with SubVersion.
In today&amp;rsquo;s world of distributed version control systems like Git &amp;amp; Mercurial,
using SubVersion may seem quaint but that&amp;rsquo;s the cost of using a stable legacy
package like FuseCompress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo aptitude install subversion
svn checkout http://fusecompress.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/ fusecompress-read-only
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Run the fusecompress build process
Change to the folder where you&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded the fusecompress sources and
run the following commands. Put the generated fusecompress binary somewhere
in your system path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./autogen.sh
./configure
make
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Using fusecompress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The least disruptive way I found to use fusecompress is to simply mount the compressed
folders exactly where they currently are. The key thing to remember while using
fusecompress is that it compress files when they get written to disk. So files that
are already in the folder won&amp;rsquo;t automatically get compressed. The way I typically
manage this is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rename the directory you want to compress&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mv directoryname temporaryname
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create an empty directory with the old name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir directoryname
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fusecompress the directory&lt;/strong&gt;
The default compression algorithm used is LZO which is very fast. You can also
use LZMA as indicated below to get a better compression ratio. You maw want to
add this line to your ~/.profile to automount on boot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;fusecompress directoryname
fusecompress -c lzma directoryname
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Move back all the contents&lt;/strong&gt;
Since Fusecompress will now compress each of the files as it is moved back, this
step will take quite a bit of time depending on the amount of data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd temporaryname
mv *.* ../directoryname
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>