<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>About on Curiosity &amp; the Geek Blog </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>/tags/about/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 02:50:25 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Hariharan Srinath</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 02:50:25 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been driven by curiosity since my childhood and my life took a decidedly geeky turn at the age of eleven
in early 90s when I taught myself computer programming in the BASIC Language from IBM Personal Computer manuals
in my father&amp;rsquo;s office. Though I have pursued other avenues in higher education and career, coding has been a
lifelong hobby to which I have recently added tinkering with hobby electronics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have degrees in Metallurgical Engineering (&lt;a href=&#34;http://iitbhu.ac.in/&#34;&gt;Indian Institute of Technology, Benaras
Hindu University, Varanasi&lt;/a&gt;) and Management (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iimahd.ernet.in/&#34;&gt;Indian Institute of Management, Ahmedabad&lt;/a&gt;).
I contributed to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.saimm.co.za/Conferences/MoltenSlags2004/077-Ekengard.pdf&#34;&gt;paper on steel-making&lt;/a&gt;
during my undergraduate internship in the Royal Institute of Technology, Stockholm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been working at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pg.com&#34;&gt;Procter &amp;amp; Gamble&lt;/a&gt; since 2006 in the field of &lt;a href=&#34;http://india.experiencepg.com/home/consumer_market_knowledge0.html&#34;&gt;consumer insights &amp;amp; analytics&lt;/a&gt;.
The major area of expertise I have developed over the years is in emerging market sales &amp;amp;
distribution recently leading analytic capabilities in this space globally. I also have significant experience in the
areas of traditional &amp;amp; digital media planning, modern retail, segmentation, trial/sampling programs and application
of behavioral science to consumer communications.  I currently work in a global innovation role focused on
developing new insights &amp;amp; analytics capabilities using emerging technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am based out of Mumbai, married to Deepa and we have a daughter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>